Patricia Szkarlat

C: 416.803.0653 **E:** szkarlat@mac.com **W:** github.com/patszkarlat



Profile

Emerging full-stack web developer with infectious zeal for technology, training and design. Jane-of-all-trades, wearer of many hats. Inquisitive, uncovers gaps, organizes and analyzes data to strengthen and maximize business performance. Uses careful probing skills to problem-solve and expedite resolutions.

Core Expertise

- Basic to Intermediate HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, jQuery
- Adult Training & Development
- Program Development

- Facilitation & Presentation
- Team Leadership
- Certified in iLife, iWork, Aperture 3
- Graduated from Creative Strategies, Apple

Education

Bitmaker Labs

2014
Seneca College of Applied Arts and Technology, Toronto, Ontario

2004
Diploma , Graphic Design

Professional Experience

Apple Inc., Toronto, Ontario

2006 – present

Creative 2008 – present

- Recipient of consistent customer testimonials for providing excellent tutoring and facilitation, employing analogies and using non-technical language to simplify and optimize the use of various Apple products.
- Acquire a thorough knowledge of the clients' requirements through attentive probing and active listening skills, evaluate their options and recommend application and software solutions to advance their goals.
- Provide detailed one-on-one tutorial sessions to explore customers' needs and patiently answer questions, resolve technical issues, customizing training to match client skill level.
- Design proposals and consult with management on upcoming training procedures.
- Research and implement training to sales team on software and in-store support program, increasing sales revenue.

Mentor 2011 – 2012

- Appointed by the Regional Market Leader to the unique position due to the ability to engage, empower and provide guidance and support to 100+ staff in the Square One retail location.
- Act as a trusted liaison operating confidentially to provide personal and career development coaching, generating an uplift in staff morale, enthusiasm and team spirit.

Mac Genius in-training

2007 - 2008

- Promoted for showing initiative in resolving complex technical issues, the ability to interact with technical and non-technical clientele and enthusiasm for emerging technologies.
- Played a crucial team role at support bar troubleshooting Macs and iPods.
- Performed data transfers on Mac-to-Mac and PC-to-Mac for clientele.
- Set up the display Mac inventory according to a strict mandate.
- Administered a large hardware inventory, recording numerous components as received from Apple and assigned parts to customer repairs.

Mac Specialist 2006 – 2007

- Rapidly gained an understanding of customer needs and budget, positioning Apple as a viable alternative, using an in-depth knowledge of Apple hardware and software.
- Consistently recognized as a high sales performer, receiving the "Sales Person of the Month" award numerous times.

Ciba Vision Novartis, Mississauga, Ontario

2002 - 2006

Customer Service Representative

- Acknowledged for accuracy in translating a high volume of incoming orders for contact lenses stemming from optometrists and vision centres across Canada and the United States.
- Recognized for providing exceptional customer service, actively taking interest in the person behind each call.
- Traced missed shipments in partnership with couriers and transportation companies for multiple North American destinations.

Interests

Music, food, audiophile gear, dancing, motorcycles, cats, chocolate, movies